Lucas Rodrigues Da Silva

Frontend Engineer - São Paulo, Brazil

Email: lucasrds01@gmail.com | LinkedIn: bit.ly/inLucas | GitHub: bit.ly/gitLucas | Phone: +55 11 972335300

Summary

I'm a software developer focused on front-end applications with 6+ years of experience at developing enterprise applications. I'm always looking to deliver the best results and really solve customer problems.

I work mainly with technologies such as: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Angular (latest versions), RxJS, Git, Webpack, but also I have some knowledge on ReactJS, Java and Spring, AWS, Docker, MongoDB, SQL.

Experience

Frontend Engineer at Aegro July 2019 – Agosto 2022 (3 years 2 months)

- Responsible for improving the rural farmer's experience, automating processes and increasing crop productivity. I helped develop several financial and agricultural products, and maintained a farm management software. I worked in the whole life cycle of software development frontend, backend, cloud, team lead.
- I've worked with Angular (10 & 12), AngularJS, Material Design, TypeScript, RxJS, Ngrx, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Design System, Java & Spring, MongoDB, AWS (S3, Cloudfront, EC2, ELB), ArgoCD, Linux, Git.

Frontend Developer at Cedro Technologies March 2018 – March 2019 (1 year)

- I worked at the broker Guide Investimentos. My main responsibilities were to develop and maintain an admin system to register investment products like, stocks, treasury direct, managed funds. I was responsible for the frontend development, participating in the whole process of the agile team.
- As a frontend developer I could deliver high quality code and good reactive interfaces using Angular 7, RxJS, Material Design, PrimeNG, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Git, NodeJS. I was used to deploying the application using docker-compose that was connected with Jenkins. I did a lot of code reviews and helped new developers as needed.

Frontend Developer at Case Imagine March 2017 – March 2018 (1 year)

- Our team has developed a modern admin system to help the company manage their needs. The system modules include sales, payment, jobs, customer management and so on. Using agile methodologies we were able to deliver high value to the customer in a short time with a small team.
- I've done almost all client-side development and built a strong responsive and reliable SPA using AngularJS, SCSS, Bootstrap 3, HTML, Pug, JavaScript, CSS, Gulp.

Junior Software Developer at LBCA June 2015 – February 2017 (1 year 9 months)

- Responsible for developing and maintaining the Legalbox System, a web application to manage legal processes and automate the tasks of lawyers. I was able to participate in all processes such as requirements analysis, architecture and application development.
- As fullstack developer I could develop complete modules using ASP Classic and ASP.NET on the server-side; for all components on the client-side we've used HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap 3, jQuery; besides that I used to create complex SQL queries and procedures to store millions of data and to generate reports.

Education

Associate Degree: Analysis and systems development at UNICSUL 2013 – 2015

Extension courses: React v16, Node.js v8, Angular v5+, AngularJS, Algorithms, Responsive Web applications